ALL FIGURES,
INCIDENTS, LOCATIONS,
ORGANIZATIONS,
AND OTHERS ARE FICTITIOUS.
CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS
WERE FILMED SAFELY
IN ACCORDANCE WITH GUIDELINES.
What brings you here, Mr. Attorney?
Why are you here?
I don't know.
I went wherever my feet took me
and ended up here.
Why haven't you…
burned the talisman yet?
I'm not sure.
Maybe I wanted to find
even just a tiny excuse not to burn it.
But…
the more I listened to others…
the more my disappointment grew.
Now…
I'm done looking for excuses.
Despite what others say,
I've decided
to believe…
what I know and remember of you.
You were born
on August 15, 1963.
Your name is Shin Gi-jung.
You are…
my father.
-Dad!
-Sa-rang.
All right. Let's play catch, I-rang.
Good?
Dad!
You are…
…my son…
I-rang.
Dad…
Your hands used to be so tiny.
They're so big now.
Your mom…
is well, right?
She is.
And healthy?
Yes, she's very healthy.
What about Sa-rang?
Oh, right.
The paralegal called you
his brother-in-law.
He must be my son-in-law.
That's right.
He's a little silly and off the wall,
-he's really--
-Nice, I know. He's a good man.
I only got to talk to him a little,
but I could tell right away.
This is where Mom works.
Your mom runs a butcher's?
Yes.
And right next to it
is the restaurant that Sa-rang runs.
This is totally unexpected.
It's quite famous in this neighborhood.
I see.
Let's go inside.
Wait.
You'd better go alone for now.
They might be shocked if you possess me.
I'll wait at my office.
All right.
When you aren't sure about yourself,
take a deep breath and think to yourself
that you can do it.
It will bring you real courage.
Can you do this for me?
Honey.
Here you go. Enjoy.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
-You ordered the spicy pork, right?
-Yes.
Here you go.
Your spicy pork. And here's the stew.
Be careful, it's hot.
-Let me know if you need anything.
-Dad!
I want ice cream.
-"Dad"?
-Buy me ice cream.
Ice cream?
You already had chips earlier.
Save ice cream for tomorrow, Da-bong.
-You must be my granddaughter.
-Ice cream and chips are different.
-Yes, I know.
-Da-bong…
-I do, but your mom doesn't.
-What a lovely name.
Hmph. I hate you, Mom!
I hate you too!
Da-bong.
Watch how you speak to your dad.
Sa-rang?
My daughter…
My sweetheart, Sa-rang.
Welcome.
Da-bong, we'll talk again later.
-No.
-What do you mean, no?
Were you being good or naughty?
-Pork belly, sir? Got it.
-I was naughty.
I-rang.
You must have
a lot of questions to ask me.
What?
You said I deceived people.
Also…
you said that
I'd want to die again out of shame
if you told me who I was.
Can you tell me why you said such a thing?
I honestly don't remember
my last moment.
Nor do I remember how I died.
What I can recall is
that I was on my way
to collect crucial evidence
for Mr. Yoon's case that day.
Three minutes left to arrive.
I'm not sure
what happened next.
There was an accident.
You were taken to the ER,
but you died
before we arrived.
And…
I…
want to hear your side of the story,
not what others say about you.
What I know…
Okay.
The first time I met Mr. Yoon was
because of a school violence case.
Public outrage was boiling over
with a lot of people saying
that the teacher ruined a student
through excessive punishment.
But when we first met,
Mr. Yoon was quite firm.
A teacher must teach their students
to be responsible for their mistakes.
I see.
INVESTIGATION REPORT
INTERROGATION REPORT
EXPULSION WAS ENFORCED
CRIMINAL AND INVESTIGATION RECORDS
Upon actual investigation,
it turned out that the teacher's decision
about the bullies was fair.
-No!
-Damn, it stinks so much.
For the breach of Article 17,
the duty to maintain good conduct,
I order your expulsion.
-What? Expulsion?
-It's not…
I said it's not my fault.
There was nothing legally wrong, either.
NO GROUNDS FOR SUSPICION
So, I decided not to prosecute him
and thought the case was over.
MAY 12
YOON DAE-MYEONG
"Yoon Dae-myeong"?
But a few days later,
a flood of lawsuits and complaints
against Mr. Yoon began to pour in.
Complainants were parents, colleagues,
and even outside figures.
The cases were all different too.
Mr. Yoon openly humiliated my daughter.
It mentally traumatized her.
Rumors said he touched female students.
He called them in for counseling
and sneakily touched them.
There's a rumor that
he takes bribes from parents
and treats school funds for personal use.
It shows he lacks a moral compass.
Since the complaints were filed,
I had no choice
but to investigate as a prosecutor.
My conclusion was
that Mr. Yoon was moral
and upright.
The problem was that
a person like him could be…
an eyesore for some people.
An eyesore?
I thought this series of complaints
wasn't simply out of
a misunderstanding or hostility,
but an intentional act
to bring Mr. Yoon down.
I was aware of the sheer tenacity
of those who cunningly exploit the law,
so I carefully gave him a piece of advice.
Mr. Yoon.
Is there…
anyone you're in conflict with?
Some may not like me.
But that doesn't mean
I should stop myself
from doing what I must do.
With all due respect,
why don't you re-examine
your relations with those around you?
If you're in conflict with anyone,
you might want to work things out
with them smoothly.
Afterward…
It must've been three months or so.
I got a call from Mr. Yoon.
Hello?
Prosecutor Shin, I figured it out.
He probably visited those
who may have suffered because of him.
His first destination was
the bully student's house.
There, he unexpectedly saw
the student's father
with a prosecutor he'd seen
at the Prosecutors' Office.
A prosecutor?
He'd only seen him a few times
as he frequented the Prosecutors' Office.
He didn't know his name or department.
He meant to ask me about him,
but then, he thought it'd get complicated
if everything turned out
to be a misunderstanding.
So, he sought another way
to look into it carefully.
Hello?
Prosecutor Shin, I figured it out.
What do you mean by that?
I recorded their conversation.
I hid the recorder just in case.
You're the only one I can trust.
Please,
make sure to reveal the truth.
Just a moment, Mr. Yoon.
Yes.
Got it.
I'm on my way now.
And…
my memory ends
when I went to collect the recorder.
That day,
Mr. Yoon
was found to have committed suicide.
What?
That's absurd.
The last time we spoke,
he was full of hope
that he'd be cleared of false charges.
But he killed himself?
Did I…
die on the same day as Mr. Yoon?
Yes.
And your body tested positive
for narcotics.
Your cabinet was
filled with evidence of corruption.
Narcotics
and evidence of corruption?
I don't get it.
People thought
you took bribes from someone
and used your position as a prosecutor
to torment Mr. Yoon relentlessly,
which caused
Mr. Yoon to commit suicide.
What are you talking about?
That's ridiculous!
It's not true.
I-rang, none of that makes sense.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I thought the same
as everyone else.
I wanted to believe otherwise,
but I blamed and resented
a corrupt prosecutor
whom the world pointed fingers at.
That's why I was so harsh on you
when you showed up.
I see.
But in the end,
you decided to believe me.
The one person who believes in me.
Yes, that.
That's all I need.
What I remembered of you…
was right.
From now on,
we'll set things right.
I'll do it for you.
Thank you.
I have something to tell you, Father.
Take a seat there.
I met the shaman just now.
Shin I-rang's father.
Why do you bother with him?
Shin Gi-jung died 20 years ago.
Let's say Shin I-rang
does see his father's spirit.
But what does it have to do with you?
Why do you care so much that you even
locked up the shaman in this building?
I didn't expect you'd discover all that.
Good job.
Father.
Shin Gi-jung was my direct junior.
He was a great prosecutor
of unmatched diligence
and had profound insight in every case.
Hello?
Byung-il.
My hunch was right.
What's the occasion?
It's not like you to get so worked up.
I told you some forces were
intentionally harassing Mr. Yoon.
It was a senior prosecutor.
What are you talking about?
A prosecutor took bribes
from the bully student's father
and targeted Mr. Yoon for investigation.
What… Are you sure about this?
Act rashly
and you might get the blunt end
of being labeled as a whistleblower.
So I'm going to double-check it.
Mr. Yoon told me
where he hid the recorded evidence.
I'm on my way to collect it.
Gi-jung.
Be careful.
Of course, I will.
Don't worry.
I'll talk to you again when I'm back.
But I didn't hear from him after that.
Later that night, I was informed
Gi-jung and Mr. Yoon were found dead.
So what?
Shin Gi-jung is
the only person who knows
where the recorder is.
Why are you so concerned
with this recorder?
I'm the chief prosecutor
who harassed Yoon Dae-myeong
at the bully student's father's request.
What?
Why, Father?
I did it to survive.
At the time, I was losing my footing
after the chief prosecutor I served
was sidelined.
That was when I got an offer.
DAEHUN LAW FIRM
I heard you're looking
for a law firm to join.
If you quietly take care
of my daughter's case,
I'll bring you on board
with preferential treatment.
Well,
I can do that much myself.
I'm not sure
if it's worth taking such a risk.
Then what do you want in exchange?
A future.
A guaranteed future
that can never be shaken.
PERSONAL BACKGROUND INFORMATION
NAME: YOON DAE-MYEONG
It was the first and last time
I ever abandoned my convictions
as a man of the law.
I hired people
to file complaints and lawsuits.
Yoon Dae-myeong gave up on his life
too easily.
And then,
I became the owner of Taebaek.
Did you
kill Yoon Dae-myeong
and Shin Gi-jung?
No.
I didn't kill anyone.
CHARCOAL BRIQUETTE
Like I said, he was so hopeless
that he took his own life.
And Shin Gi-jung died
in an unfortunate accident.
Yeah?
It's all been taken care of.
I had no idea
Gi-jung was using drugs.
Additionally, all of his other
corrupt acts were found in his cabinet.
That's what happened.
Shin Gi-jung committed the corruption,
but I can't say I'm fully innocent.
Are you disappointed in me?
No.
I finally feel a connection to you.
You trusted me
and told me everything honestly.
If Shin Gi-jung's spirit is back,
he'll try to find the recorder for sure.
He'll try to suffocate me with it.
If no one stops him,
Taebaek will go down.
No.
Taebaek will never go down, Father.
Don't worry.
I'll stop him.
There are people better suited
for this kind of work.
Don't make any rash moves.
Wait for the perfect moment.
Yes, Father.
Is there anyone else
who knows about the recorder
other than Mr. Yoon?
Yes.
Who?
Chief Prosecutor Yang Byung-il.
He was my senior.
I know him.
He's the chairman
of a big law firm named Taebaek.
It can't be him.
We were like brothers.
The culprit
tried to stop the evidence from going out
even by killing you and Mr. Yoon.
You know where the recorder is, right?
The Yoon Dae-myeong case?
I checked the records Mr. Yoon collected
and noticed a lot of issues
in the initial investigation.
Na-hyun, it was closed
as suicide 20 years ago.
It may not be just one.
-What?
-The victim, I mean.
If Mr. Yoon was murdered,
the death of Shin Gi-jung, who died
on the same day, is suspicious as well.
There may be a connection.
So, how do you want me to help?
I want to meet the first witness.
There are parts
where the statement doesn't add up.
The witness said
he discovered the scene at 10 p.m.
But the record says
the report was made at 3 a.m.
He also said
the police were already there,
but there's no dispatch record
at the local police station.
It happened a long time ago.
The witness may not still be in Korea
or may no longer be alive.
Still, look into it for me.
I won't give you personal details.
I'll contact him and ask
if he's okay to meet you.
Thanks.
Looking for something?
Mom.
Where is
the brown handbag Dad bought you
when you were newlyweds?
Why do you need it all of a sudden?
-The thing is--
-Did…
your dad say he put something in it?
But Mom…
how did you know?
A few days ago,
I found a paper crane
in the lunch box I packed for you.
The same paper crane your dad used to put
in his lunch box.
Then,
why did you act like
you didn't know?
The truth is…
when I heard you could see ghosts,
I hoped your dad would come.
As I saw you right wrongs for the ghosts,
my wish grew bigger.
But…
I knew how painful and hard it'd be
for you to meet your dad again,
so I couldn't bring myself to tell you.
Mom.
It turned out
Dad was framed.
Where is he?
At the office.
When everything is over,
he wants to meet the family
with his head held high.
He's a ghost now,
but he's still so inflexible.
Okay. Bring him home
after everything is taken care of.
And tell him
that I, Park Gyeong-hwa,
believe what Shin Gi-jung says
even if the world comes to an end.
Okay.
This is Yang Do-kyung.
Oh.
I heard from the Chairman.
I was waiting for your call
to tell you something.
I'm listening.
One of my boys got a call
from a prosecutor just a while ago.
He said an attorney wanted to inquire
about the Yoon case from 20 years ago.
Who's that?
I looked into this attorney he mentioned.
Her name is Han Na-hyun.
She's a colleague of Shin I-rang.
If the Chairman hears this--
Don't mind her.
Why's that?
Attorney Han is one of us.
Leave her be.
This is where you wanted to come with me?
Yeah.
I wanted to come.
This place hasn't changed.
I always dropped by
whenever I faced big cases.
All dressed up like that?
I've worn the suit for 22 years
and I can't take it off.
I came here with you sometimes
when you were little, remember?
I do.
I should be peeling it for you.
But I can't even hold it.
I can do it on my own now.
Dad.
Dad!
You have to give me a warning.
You used to like it when I peeled it
and dipped it in salt for you like this.
It's good.
Boiled eggs are good
at the bathhouse indeed.
They are.
Hard to swallow, right?
SUJEONG BATHHOUSE
Shall we go?
PITTER-PATTER BUTCHER-STYLE BBQ
Mr. Yang.
What brings you here?
Stop what you're doing now.
Why?
You don't have to return to Taebaek.
You can work with Shin I-rang.
But don't try to discover the truth
behind this case.
-Why shouldn't I discover the truth?
-It's dangerous.
You know what I'm up to
and that it's dangerous.
Then, you must know
who'll put me in danger.
Who is it?
I'm telling you
because I care about you
and we were colleagues once.
I warned you.
Prosecutor Kim?
Hi, Na-hyun.
I went over the Yoon Dae-myeong case
after you left.
The first witness was
a member of the Four Dragons Gang
which was dismantled
in Chinatown 20 years ago.
A Four Dragons member?
What's more important is
that the prosecutor
who dismantled the gang
was Shin Gi-jung.
OCTOBER 10, 2003
SEOMGANG ELECTRONICS
I'm the son of Prosecutor Shin Gi-jung
from the Incheon Prosecutors' Office.
SHIN I-RANG LAW OFFICE
PITTER-PATTER BUTCHER-STYLE BBQ
Attorney Shin?
It's not him.
Who are you?
Why aren't you saying anything?
I can't be sure
if you're allies
or enemies
with my I-rang.
Enemies?
You don't know how much I like…
I mean, help him.
Oh, check the necklace.
My number's engraved on it.
SHIN I-RANG
010-0976-1425
ATTORNEY SHIN I-RANG
ATTORNEY HAN NA-HYUN
010-0976-1425
See?
So, who are you?
Why do you call Attorney Shin "my I-rang"?
Are you a friend of his?
Or… a family member?
-Yes.
-What?
Nice to meet you.
I know it may be confusing,
but I'm I-rang's dad…
Shin Gi-jung.
Forgive me for being rude--
No, that's okay.
Um…
Father.
Excuse me for being disrespectful.
I'm so sorry.
No, please don't be.
I'm rather glad
to see how much you care about my son.
It was nice.
Let me officially introduce myself.
I'm colleagues with Attorney Shin I-rang.
I'm Attorney Han Na-hyun.
Nice to meet you.
So, why aren't you waking him up?
If you don't know how, let me--
No, that's not it.
I just…
This recorder has a conversation
between those who framed Mr. Yoon.
If it holds any kind of truth
that may put I-rang in danger…
I'd like for him to be unaware of it.
I cannot put my son in danger
trying to resolve my own resentment.
Attorney Shin remembered you
as a righteous hero.
Although you passed away
under false accusations,
he wanted to believe in you to the end.
That led him to become an attorney.
Your son is more diligent
and responsible than anyone.
He's handled a lot of difficult cases
on his own.
I'm sure he will do the same this time.
Attorney Han.
Thank you for letting me realize…
that I should…
leave the decision to him.
Could you wake him up?
Sure.
Attorney Han?
Are you okay?
Why are we…
I met your father.
And…
I know what that recorder is.
I'm sorry for keeping it from you.
It's all right.
I've been through it, you know.
You were right.
I was
greatly mistaken about my dad.
It's such a relief.
You should check the recording now.
Listen to it with me.
Let's go inside.
Okay.
Hello?
Shin I-rang arrived
at the office just now.
PITTER-PATTER BUTCHER-STYLE BBQ
Get the recorder from him first.
Sure, but…
Attorney Han Na-hyun is with him.
What do we do about her?
Do-kyung.
Who are you people?
Wow.
I love the vibe of this office.
It's perfect for a funeral.
Oh, that must be it.
-Bring it over.
-Says who?
I-rang.
Trust me and grab that thing.
Fine.
Here, take it.
You still haven't turned over a new leaf,
Lee Tae-geon?
What?
-Boss!
-Are you okay, sir?
What are you waiting for? Get him!
Go get her, boys.
Head!
Shin I-rang!
I don't care if you're ghost or human.
The recorder.
Bring it here.
Wait.
I get it,
so stop.
No, I-rang. Don't do it.
I can't let you go like this.
I'm sorry.
Drag him here.
You'll never get to listen to this.
Got it?
Shin I-rang!
I'll never lose it again.
SPECIAL THANKS TO
CHOI WON-YOUNG AND JUNG JAE-SUNG
SHIN I-RANG
010-0976-1425
Welcome.
It…
It must've been a long way… Oof!
-I'll go again.
-Okay, cut.
Mister.
I want to go there.
Are you…
Hello?
Let's go again.
You're going back in there?
They thought I was a woman--
They thought I was a gangster
and cornered me.
Sorry!
My bad.
The shine of his cheap shoes shows
his diligent nature.
The leather surface appears
to be in good condition,
which shows…
I'm sorry.
Tae-in, you do it.
Do we have a large party?
I-rang is strange.
Oh, sorry. That's not the line.
Ow, that hurts.
It didn't break.
Subtitle translation by: Eunjin Erica Kim